<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>rose.codes - Review</title>
	<subtitle>Thoughts on everything. By a programmer.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://rose.codes/categories/review/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://rose.codes"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2021-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://rose.codes/categories/review/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Finnish Way - A Book Review</title>
		<published>2021-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://rose.codes/blog/the-finnish-way/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://rose.codes/blog/the-finnish-way/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The author of &lt;em&gt;The Finnish Way&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is an immigrant to Finland who fell in love with the country&#x27;s culture and what the locals call &amp;quot;Sisu.&amp;quot; She compiles a set of related life-lessons she&#x27;s gained. It&#x27;s an easy read and I enjoyed it. I&#x27;ve incorporated some of the lessons of this book into my own life, including fun ones like cold-dipping. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;continue-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ll start out with a chapter synopsis. Not neccessarily complete. Just as I personally interpretted. Then I&#x27;ll give my personal takeaways from this book. Then I&#x27;ll make a general assessment and recommendation of the book.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-1&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cycle or walk to work or school&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approach chores such as cleaning as a workout&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First try to fix items before throwing away and buying new.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy things that last.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take stairs instead of elevator&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embrace nature, whatever the weather or season&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-2&quot;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strive for Sisu - mental toughness, fortitude, resilience. Stubborn courageous attitude. Transforms challenges into opportunities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;em&gt;How&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; can I do this?&amp;quot; Instead of &amp;quot;I can&#x27;t&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;I won&#x27;t&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good health and well-being can help build up Sisu.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-3&quot;&gt;Chapter 3&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 to 60 second dip into 4 degree Celsius water has many health benefits
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improves cold tolerance&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improves immunity&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gives pain relief&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#x27;s a natural stimulant&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides stress relief&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But don&#x27;t do it if you are
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sick&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suffering from heart condition, high blood pressure, asthma&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider neoprene slippers, flip-flops, or wool socks as you walk to the water.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-4&quot;&gt;Chapter 4&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal of a sauna is to relax both body and mind&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even a few minutes in the hot steam can work&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sauna Etiquette
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no rules about how long to sit in the sauna&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay hydrated by drinking water&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always ask the other sauna-goers if it&#x27;s all right before puring the loylly (water ladle) on the hot rocks.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can wrap up in a towel or be naked (if you&#x27;re brave)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-5&quot;&gt;Chapter 5&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being in nature can reduce stress and anxiety and alleviate mild depression, even a 15 min walk in a park or forest or shoreline.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try digital detox by putting screens on silent when in nature.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on surroundings and be present. Notice color of tree leaves or flowers. Helps to take a break from whatever is on your mind.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a way to recharge Sisu.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-6&quot;&gt;Chapter 6&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food plate should be 1&#x2F;2 veggies, 1&#x2F;4 starches, 1&#x2F;4 protein.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grocery cart should probably be same ratio&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rainbow method - How many colors are represented by items on plate? Generally more = better&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add fruits and berries to morning oatmeal or cereal, or just eat them direct&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink water as your drink of choice&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grow some of your own produce&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-7&quot;&gt;Chapter 7&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unstructured outdoor play, rain or shine, is important for kids. Weather should not be an excuse.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage a connection with nature in kids. Let them climb, jump and run outdoors.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let kids build their own stuff out of used items like cereal boxes instead of buying new toys&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play is how kids learn&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cultivate a supportive environment for not giving up&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-8&quot;&gt;Chapter 8&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cycling has many health benefits&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Counters effects of sedentary lifestyle&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elevates mood&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides stress relief&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boosts creativity&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boosts brain power&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cycling can save time &amp;amp; money compared to owning and maintaining a car&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep cycling enjoyable. Even shorter distances are great.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find cycling friends&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research bike-friendly trails in area&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider the positive experience of author in an area with significant biking infrastructure.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-9&quot;&gt;Chapter 9&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movement is medicine. Find opportunities to move and exercise in every-day life. Sprinkle movement across your day.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;chapter-10&quot;&gt;Chapter 10&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead of buying or outsourcing a well-being service, can you do it yourself or with a friend?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is buying secondhand an option?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where will item go when I&#x27; done with it? Can it be donated or resold?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invest in a few quality, well-made items that will last.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the effort to design a more functional lifestyle where possible. This is an act of Sisu. Can anything be downsized without adversely affecting you or your family, that could reduce maintenance costs or commute time?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are things that stood out to me personally after reading &lt;em&gt;The Finnish Way&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would be amazing to live in a place that was TRULY bike-friendly. Imaging biking to work, to stores, to family and friends, without worrying about cars. I&#x27;m in Granger, Indiana right now, and while there are some new bike paths that are truly great, there is a lot of room for improvement, both in Granger and the surrounding South Bend &#x2F; Mishawaka &#x2F; Elkhart area.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chores are also workouts&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nature should be enjoyed no matter the season or weather, which is doable when properly prepared for&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cold dips and Sauna are healthy for body &amp;amp; mind&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes we need a digital detox&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A healthy diet is 1&#x2F;2 veggie, 1&#x2F;4 starch, 1&#x2F;4 protein&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play is how kids learn, and outdoor play the traditional and most healthy way that happens. Kids need a lot of unstructured play.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intentionally sprinkle your day with movement.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be concerned about health and sustainability, both personal and at a society level.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually read this book a couple years ago. Here are the lessons that I still apply to my life to this day:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking cold dips. Lake Michigan is great for this! Just don&#x27;t go when there&#x27;s significant ice. And don&#x27;t go alone. Most of the time it&#x27;s simply me dipping in a cold bath. I&#x27;ve even had the kids (voluntarily of course) join me on some cold dips. They loved it!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#x27;ve made permanent changes to my diet that include avoiding all the added sugars, processed grains, and dairy that are in our food. It&#x27;s made significant improvements in my health. I encourage people to work hard at building a diet for themselves that makes them happy and healthy. Everyone is different so it takes research. But this book played a part in my journey.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I always keep in mind that my kids need some outdoor time. We went camping 6 times this year!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Screentime limits remain important in my family.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend this book to any American sick of the default diet and behaviors that our culture tries to make you emulate. If you want to take a step toward being more intentional in your self-care, this book is an easy read, and a fascinating glimpse into some unique and positive aspects of Finnish culture.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you buy the book with this link I&#x27;ll get a small commision.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.com&#x2F;gp&#x2F;product&#x2F;0143132997&#x2F;ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0143132997&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=rosecodes-20&amp;amp;linkId=d9a5eefa539376539ec31731e6ac1acf&quot;&gt;The Finnish Way: Finding Courage, Wellness, and Happiness Through the Power of Sisu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
